你好
Hi.
像是个不错的派对
Sounds like a good party.
-20美金  -行  没问题
- Twenty bucks. - Okay, no problem.
我的钱  就在  就在这里
I, uh, just- I got it in here somewhere.
听着  我
Oh, you know, I'm-
对不起  我一定是忘了取钱了
I'm sorry. I guess I must have forgotten to go to the machine.
没错  你还忘了刷牙
Yeah, and brush your teeth.
女士  你一分钱都没有
Lady, you don't have two cents.
我能  能找我朋友拿  他就在里面
Well, I can- I can get it from- from my friend who's inside.
他会给我钱的
He can give it to me,
-然后我再出来给你  -你一个人都不认识
- and then I'll bring it back out to you. - You don't know anybody here.
我认识的  他叫詹姆斯  还是金发
Yes, I do. James. He's blond,
人很好  而且很爱说话的
and he's really friendly, and he's a big talker.
我要见他
I need to see him.
进去吧
Go on in.
詹姆斯
James?
-詹姆斯  -你好
- James? - Hi.
知道詹姆斯在哪里吗
Do you know where James is?
知道啊  他  他就在附近
Oh, yeah, he's- he's around here somewhere.
我们去找他
Let's go find him.
詹姆斯  看到詹姆斯了吗
James? Do you know whereJames is?
詹姆斯在哪里
Where is James?
詹姆斯  詹姆斯
James? James?
-对  他  他在附近  -在哪里
- Oh, yeah, he's- he's around here somewhere. - Where is he?
求你了  我真的要找他
Please. I really need to find him.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
贱人
Bitch!
不  她想要帮我
No! She's trying to help me!
放开她  放开我
Get off her! Get off me!
安静
Settle down!
起来
Move!
天  我压根没碰过她
Geez. I didn't touch her.
这下好了  现在要去医院了
Great. Now we gotta go to a hospital.
病人无家可归
Homeless.
24小时前入院  怀疑吸毒过量
Admitted 24 hours ago with a suspected drug overdose.
毒品检测呈阴性  但仍有妄想症状
Her tox screen's clean, but she's still delusional.
"无家可归"通常表示疯狂  没钱
"Homeless." Usually means crazy, no money.
-卡迪不会  -我们是教学医院
- Cuddy's not gonna be - We're a teaching hospital.
没有身份证  都不知道她叫什么
No I D. Doesn't even seem to know her name.
找我来是因为她手臂上的病灶
I got called in because of some lesions on her arm.
无家可归通常没有庇护所  会日照过度
Homeless always means no roof. Leads to too much sun.
不  病灶是良性的
No, the lesions were noncancerous.
不过我注意到她手腕抽搐
But I noticed a twitch. Her wrist.
你感觉到了
You feel that?
当然  我是人
Sure. I'm human.
握紧我的手指  越紧越好
Make a fist around my fingers as tight as you can.
-握紧  -我正在握
- Squeeze. - I am.
行
All right.
举起手臂  过头
Raise your arms above your head for me.
她在痉挛
She's seizing.
拿安定来
Get me some Ativan.
她不想出院  她在骗你
She doesn't wanna be discharged. She's manipulating you.
痉挛是真的  检查下血糖
It's real. Check a finger stick.
血糖38
Blood sugar's 38.
50%葡萄糖  静推  马上
I need D-50 I.V. Push, stat.
假装低血糖  演技派啊
Fake low blood sugar. Now, that's acting.
低血糖是真的
The blood sugar was real.
她可能患有糖尿病  胰岛素服用过量
She's probably diabetic. O.D.'d on her own insulin.
2032室的病人的随身物品在这里吗
Room 2032. Do you have her effects out here?
听着  痉挛的发作
Look, a seizure
能让她在医生检查时有个睡觉的地方
buys her a place to sleep while the nice doctors run their tests.
或许还有几顿免费餐
Maybe a few free meals.
20块  赌里面有胰岛素
Twenty bucks says there's insulin in there.
哇  求你收起来吧
Oh! Wow. Put this back, please.
-抽搐怎么说  -她胳膊动了
- What about the twitch? - Her arm moved.
为何要装抽搐呢  痉挛还不够严重吗
Why fake a twitch? In case the seizure was too subtle?
抽搐可能是肿瘤引起  表示
The twitch could indicate a tumor, which could indicate-
有必要看神经科医生  也是为何你叫我来
A need to see a neurologist, which is why you called me.
把她留院观察到下午2点
Keep an eye on her till 2:00 P.M.
监测她的血糖  给顿热饭吃
Watch her blood sugar, give her a nice hot lunch.
然后让她出院
Then discharge her.
-他错了  -福曼错了吗
- He's wrong. - Foreman is wrong?
神经科医生在神经学问题上搞错了
The neurologist is wrong about a neurological problem.
他就看了她一眼  就说她在耍诈
He took one look at her and figured it was a scam.
所以你觉得是他主观臆断
So you figure he's not being objective.
豪斯  这个女人抽搐了  突发痉挛
House, the woman had a twitch. She had a seizure.
-福曼都看到了吗  -他只想赶她走
- Both of which Foreman saw? - He just wanted her out the door!
冷静点  小伙子
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Back up there, big fella.
你该去找福曼发泄怒火
Foreman's the guy you wanna take a swing at.
我只是希望她能得到应有的治疗
I just want her to get some medical attention.
真相绝非如此
That's not even close to being true.
肯定是其它原因  私人原因
It's something else. Something personal.
把病历给我
Give me the file.
看来会很有趣
Looks like this'll be fun.
抽搐可能是失神发作  和糖尿病无关
The twitch could be a miniseizure, unrelated to the diabetes.
脑部肿瘤吗
Brain tumor?
很高兴你能参与讨论  艾瑞克
Glad you could join us, Eric.
腕部抽搐的鉴别诊断是什么
What's the differential for a twitch in the wrist?
病人是个30岁左右的无名氏
The patient's a 30-ish Jane Doe.
要我就直接让她出院
I thought I just discharged her.
她是我的病人  听听他人意见也无害
Well, she's my patient. No harm in a second opinion.
脑部受过重创吗  硬膜下血肿
A blow to the head? A subdural hematoma?
看看病历  没有头部创伤迹象
Read the file. No evidence of cranial trauma.
抽搐可能是脑部肿瘤症状
A twitch could indicate a brain tumor.
或者是无数其它原因
Or about a dozen other things!
够了  无家可归者有两件事是拿手的
Come on. There's two things homeless people are good at-
生病和耍花招
getting sick and running scams.
要是那么担心是脑部肿瘤
If you're so worried about it being a brain tumor,
就给她做个核磁共振
get her an M.R.I.
等结果出来不是了  就能赶她走了
When she's clear on that, then you can bounce her out of here.
你都把她看透了啊
Well, you've got her all figured out.
我认识的无家可归者比你多得多
I've known a lot more homeless people than you have.
是啊  你如此了解无家可归者
Yes, you've got that going for you.
我怎么能怀疑你的医学见解呢
How could I have doubted your medical opinion?
关键的问题  你们都没注意到
The big question. You're missing it, all of you.
天
Oh, geez.
她是谁
Who is she?
行了  我们为何接这个病例
Okay, why are we on this case?
就因为威尔森要求吗
Just because Wilson asked?
这个理由还不够充分吗
Do I need a better reason?
多数人不要  但你需要
Well, most people wouldn't. You do.
关于无名氏  我们唯一确定的是
The only thing we know for sure about Jane Doe
她的名字不是无名氏
is that her name isn't Jane Doe,
就是说没有医疗记录
which means no medical history.
过敏  用药史  过往诊断  治疗
Allergies, medication, previous diagnoses, treatment-
我们没有原始资料以及治疗相关背景
We have no baseline, no context for medical treatment.
哇  看着像是胰岛素
Wow. Looks just like insulin.
呕吐  还湿的
Vomit. Still moist.
你怎么想  几天前的吗
What do you think? Couple of days old?
噢  你想让我骂人吗
Ugh! You trying to make me hurl?
对  精彩收场
Yeah. And here's the big finish.
咸的
Salty.
化学物质失衡
Chemical imbalance.
-低镁血症会导致抽搐  -或者高钙
- Low magnesium could cause a twitch. - Or high calcium.
或者是个巧合  重点是
Or it's a coincidence. The point is,
我们什么都不知道
we don't know anything.
所以做核磁共振  找出来
So do the M.R.I. Find out.
核磁共振可以等等再做  先补充电解质
The M.R.I. can wait. Hang a banana bag.
维持24小时  纠正电解质紊乱
Give her 24 hours to correct the electrolyte imbalance.
然后我们再继续
We'll take it from there.
不错  多谢
Great. Thanks.
好的  就算她没装
Okay, even if she's not faking,
这个病例哪点吸引着你
what's so fascinating about this case
目前而言  你那不想我接这个病例的态度
At the moment, how much you don't want me to take it.
让我觉得十分有趣
That's pretty fascinating.
把福曼医生的画的真像啊
Nice likeness of Dr. Foreman.
这是有史以来最帅的一张了
In fact, he's never looked better.
看的出他不喜欢我
He doesn't like me. I can tell.
没关系  他也不喜欢我
It's okay. He doesn't like me either.
谁是詹姆斯
Who's James?
头疼吗
Pain in your head?
放开我
Get away from me!
让她冷静下来
let's cool her out.
1毫克安定  推注
One milligram Ativan, push.
不要  不要  不要
No! No, no, no, no, no, no!
她咬我
She bit me!
好消息是  她没有艾滋和丙肝
Good news is, she's negative for HIV and Hep "C."
我去打针破伤风  给她做核磁共振
Yeah? I'm getting a tetanus shot. She's getting an M.R.I.
非紧急核磁共振要等两天
There's a two-day wait for nonemergency M.R.I.'s.
马上给她做核磁共振  做完就送走
She's getting an M.R.I.! Then she's outta here.
不过泰哈克医生明确说过
But Dr. Terhark specifically said
我的核磁共振检查在上午10点
I'd have the M.R.I. At 10:00.
现在都快11点了  我预检都还没呢
It's almost 11:00, and I haven't even had the pre-test yet.
抱歉  我们有点忙
Sorry. We're a little backed up.
打扰  你是泰哈克医生10点的病人吗
Excuse me. You're Dr. Terhark's 10:00?
我是安吉拉·惠特尼
I'm Angela Whitney.
我11点半要见我的装璜师
I'm meeting my decorator at 11:30.
她大老远从纽约来
She's coming all the way from New York.
泰哈克医生曾许诺我能及时赶上
Dr. Terhark promised I'd be home in time.
当然
Of course.
她打算做核磁共振的预检吗
She just about prepped for her M.R.I.?
惠特尼太太吗
Mrs. Whitney?
你们企图偷别人的检查
You tried to steal someone else's test.
泰哈克医生是整形外科医生
Dr. Terhark is a plastic surgeon.
这女人是为6个月前的下颚填充术做复诊
The woman was getting a six-month checkup on her chin implants.
-不敢相信你竟然允许他们这么做  -真的吗
- I can't believe you authorized this. - Really?
听着就是我的一贯作风
It sounds exactly like something I'd do.
她不能做核磁共振
She can't have an M.R.I.
断层扫描显示她手臂里有接骨钉
The C.T. Scan shows she has a surgical pin in her arm.
核磁共振会把它从她体内吸出来的
The M.R.I. Magnet would have ripped it out of her body.
你们看喜欢外星人电影吗
You like the Alien movies?
你们没有医疗记录  在想什么呢
You had no medical history. What were you thinking?
我们会手术取出接骨钉
We'll surgically remove the pin,
然后做核磁共振  行吗
then do the M.R.I. Does that sound good?
她是电解质失衡
She has an electrolyte imbalance.
福曼医生  一个神经科专家
Dr. Foreman, a neurologist,
他相信这女人有脑部肿瘤
believes this woman has a brain tumor.
实际上  我
Actually, I-
永远不要为医学见解道歉
Hey, don't ever apologize for a medical opinion.
要是他对了而我们没做检查  病人会死
If he's right and we don't do this test, the patient dies.
我知道你有你的专长领域
I realize that you have a specialty of your own,
不过你的专长和大脑有关吗
but does yours have anything to do with the brain?
那可是他的专长领域
His does.
行
Fine.
不过在弄清她身份前  不准做其它检查了
But nothing more until you find out who she is.
我们怎么才能
How are we supposed to-
他认识的无家可归者多了去了  无人能及啊
Hey! He knows more homeless people than any of us.
去问问她的邻居  跟踪狂
Go check out the hood, dog.
我不知道
I don't know.
我在附近见过好多人
I've seen a lot of faces around here,
但我不记得见过她
but I don't think I know her.
好吧
Great.
那个...我喜欢你的外套
Say, I, uh, like that jacket.
对  现在想起来了
Yeah, uh, it's all comin' to me now.
我知道她的东西放哪里
I know where she keeps her stuff.
就是蝙蝠罢了
Just bats.
我以为衬里会厚点
I thought the lining would be thicker.
没有肿瘤  什么都没  她的大脑没事
No tumor. Nothing. Her brain is clear.
意味着那女孩要去做手术
Which means that girl had surgery
那样你才不会被卡迪骂
just so you wouldn't get reamed out by Cuddy.
没必要  她仍有可能有些神经上的问题
Not necessarily. There could still be something neurological going on.
是啊  她没骗我们  骗我们的是核磁共振
Sure. She's not conning us. The M.R.I. is.
这种天气不穿外套
Not wearing a coat in this weather.
-太不正常了  -她画了这些
- That is so wrong. - She drew these.
可能给我们些提示
They might give us a clue.
她签名了吗  可以从她的名字着手
She sign them? Her name would be a start.
所有的神秘故事  地点
All the mythology, the locations,
都源于她的生活经历
they'd all depend on her life experience.
费城
Philadelphia.
看那天际线
Look at that skyline.
非常有共鸣啊
It's very evocative.
克莱斯勒大厦
The Chrysler Building.
-那是云  -克莱斯勒大厦在纽约
- That's a cloud. - And the Chrysler Building's in New York.
我越来越费城了
Ehh, I'm getting Philly.
仙人掌  那是  那是一辆撞烂了的车
And that cactus, well, it's a- it's a smashed car.
-是车祸  -仙人掌在费城吗
- It's a car accident. - A cactus in Philadelphia?
-水  10月是雨季  对吗  -对
- Water. Well, water's October, right? - Obviously.
22页  那就是2002年10月2号
Well, the page number 22, so that's October 2, 2002.
因此  病人2年前10月经历一场车祸
Ergo, the patient was in a car accident two years ago last October.
老天  她没事吗
My goodness. Was she okay?
断了胳膊吧
Broke her arm, I think.
他们用这个修复了
They fixed it with this.
接骨钉
Surgical pin.
比钱包好多了
Better than a wallet.
为了以备召回  接骨钉序列号和病人姓名对应
Serial numbers in case of recall, tied to a patient's name.
所以你就坚持要做核磁共振吗
That's why you insisted on the M.R.I.
就为了把接骨钉从她胳膊里取出来
so you could remove the surgical pin from her arm?
你不认为我是
You didn't think I was
为了替你收拾残局吗
gonna do it to save your sorry ass, did you?
你该看看那个
You might wanna take a look at that.
她的名字是维多利亚·马森
Her name is Victoria Matsen,
或者至少是她曾用过的名字
or at least that's the one she used then.
任何一家接诊过她的医院
Any hospital with a record of treating her
都会将相关信息发送过来
should be sending that information.
不好
Oh, crap!
她的血检结果一个小时前出来了
Her blood work came back an hour ago.
镁含量正常
Magnesium was normal.
你换她的离子输液了吗
Did you change her banana bag?
停了镁离子
Stopped the magnesium,
开始用右旋糖酐铁治疗严重贫血
started iron dextran for severe anemia.
她对右旋糖酐铁过敏
She's allergic to iron dextran.
从抢救车上拿些肾上腺素
Grab some epi off the code cart.
呼吸停止  做心肺复苏
Respiratory arrest. Call a code!
你有过敏反应  能说话吗
You're having an allergic reaction. Can you speak?
她没法呼吸
She's not getting any air.
用肾上腺素
Got the epi.
血氧饱和度降到80以下了  还再降
Sats are down in the 80s and dropping.
我们还有大概一分钟的时间
We have about another minute.
我们给她用了镇静剂  病情稳定住了
Well, we got her sedated and stabilized.
你仍然觉得她没病吗
And you still think there's nothing wrong with her?
没什么区别啊
Nothing's changed.
你差点害死她  那就是区别
You almost killed her. That's different.
我们还知道她的身份了
And we know who she is.
目前  有3家医院传来
So far, we've heard from three hospitals
维多利亚·马森的医疗记录
with records on Victoria Matsen.
过去两年中就诊7次
Seven visits going back two years.
有没有家庭住址
Any home addresses?
手臂中的接骨钉是急诊治疗时植入的
The pin in her arm went in during an E.R. visit.
她当时昏迷  所以没有问到地址
She wasn't conscious, so they didn't get an address.
其它几次就诊  她给了假地址
The other visits, she gave fake addresses.
有针对神经问题的治疗吗
Any treatment for neurological problems?
可能引发抽搐的神经问题
Anything that might explain the twitch?
去年冬天  费城的杰弗逊医院
Last winter, Jefferson Hospital in Philly.
因冻伤就诊
Got treated for frostbite.
亲爱的  外面很冷
Baby, it's cold outside.
还有抑郁症  他们给她用了百忧解
And depression. They put her on Prozac.
要我在0摄氏度住在纸箱里  我也会抑郁的
Well, I'd be bummed out too. Zero degrees, living in a box.
继续给她用百忧解
Put her back on it.
心情好了  或许能不再咬人
She cheers up, she might stop biting people.
有张哈特曼医院的去年的账单
There's a billing record from Hartman hospital last year.
两次预约  超声检查
Two appointments, ultrasounds.
-不过没说为何  -怀孕吗
- Doesn't say what for. - Pregnant?
除非是生小象
Well, only if she was expecting an elephant.
预约间隔了10个月
Appointments were ten months apart.
第一次去了  第二次放了鸽子
Kept the first, blew off the second.
腹部疼痛
Abdominal pain.
-病历上没写  -等一下
- Her chart doesn't say- - Wait a minute.
她去了第一次
She goes in the first time.
他们看了  找不到原因  10个月后
They look, they can't find anything. Ten months later,
她为何还要再去
why should she subject herself to that again?
-为何要预约  -不是她预约的
- Why make a second appointment? - She didn't.
是护士做的预约
The nurse made the appointment.
他们在找  他们在找卵巢肿瘤
They were looking- They were looking for ovarian cancer.
你得出这一结论仅凭一次取消了的预约吗
You got all of that from one canceled appointment?
杰里·郎森医生  对  他可是肿瘤专家
With Jerry Lauseng, yeah. He's an oncologist.
慢着  她当前的血检没有癌症迹象
Hang on. Her current blood work doesn't show cancer.
CA125正常[肿瘤标志物]
C.A. 125 is normal.
另外  癌症不能解释所谓的抽搐
And the cancer wouldn't account for the alleged twitch
或者任何其它所谓症状
or any ofher other alleged symptoms.
事实上  可以
Actually, it would.
癌症相关的肿瘤综合征
Neoplastic syndrome associated with the cancer...
能导致她像吃了冰毒的兔子似的抽搐
could cause her to twitch like a bunny on crystal meth.
超声检查她的卵巢
Ultrasound her ovaries.
她的核磁共振有没有显示脑肿瘤呢
Did you find a brain tumor on her M.R.I.?
没有  福曼错了
No. Foreman was wrong.
我开始怀疑这家伙的医师资格了
I'm starting to wonder about that guy's medical charts.
没错
Right.
-雪莱·戴蒙德  -在
- Shelley Diamond. - Yeah.
豪斯医生现在可以出诊了
Dr. House is ready to see you now.
小孩们又在舔来舔去了
The little ones are licking each other again,
哈利多出来的那个脚趾上
and Harry's got a seeping wart
长了个出水的疣子
on his extra toe.
我们该去哪个房间
What room should we go to?
听着  我觉得我可能染上什么了
You know what? I think I might be coming down with something.
不想传染给你们  对不起
Hate to give it to you guys. Sorry.
好吧  走吧  就像我会袖手旁观似的
Oh, yeah. Just walk out. Like I'm not gonna do anything.
再见
Bye-bye.
努力工作吗
Working hard?
这东西真不错
This stuff's pretty good.
柯林达伊卡在天才委员会工作
Calendraica works for the Council of Genius.
弗利先生是坏蛋
Bad guy is Mr. Fury.
普普通通  没什么特别才能
Fairly generic, no special skills,
不过很有条理
but apparently very well organized.
你觉得你工作努力  试试统治宇宙
You think you work hard. Try ruling the universe.
你想给我讲大道理吗
You trying to teach me something here?
图上有连衣裙  有戒指
We got the flowing dress,the ring.
觉得病人结婚了吗
Think the patient was married?
或许是不愉快的分手
Maybe it was a bad break-up.
或许因为她吸毒  老公甩了她
Maybe he dumped her 'cause she was on drugs.
-你关心她的私生活吗  -不
- You care about her personal history? - No.
问题是  你为什么不
Question is, why don't you?
我不想扯陈词滥调
I hate to cite a cliche,
不过你爸是流浪汉吗
But Dad on the streets?
-我爸和我妈一起  -都流落街头吗
- Dad's with Mom. - They're both living on the streets?
不  有养老金
No. On a pension.
那么是谁招惹你了呢
So, who pissed you off?
眼下  是你
Right now, you.
该你了  你打算告诉我为何接此病例吗
Your turn. You gonna tell me why this case?
她是我新女友  我想设计个新纹身
She's my new girlfriend. I'm having a tattoo designed.
指望你找出她的名字
I was hoping you could find out her name.
那么她不过就是另一个
So she's just another sick person that kindly
被充满爱心的威尔森医生确保
Dr. Wilson has made sure
不在庞大丑恶医疗系统中被遗忘的病人
doesn't get lost in the big, ugly system.
对  我忘了  我需要个理由说废话
Yes, I forgot. I need a reason to give a crap.
你已经说了两句废话了
You're giving two craps.
公共医疗系统总是让我困惑
The metric system always confuses me.
豪斯医生
Dr. House?
已经到女童子军饼干义卖时间了吗
Time for Girl Scout cookies already?
给我来点薄荷味巧克力华夫
Get me some thin mints.
既然你病情严重  无法进行门诊工作
Since you're too sick to work in the clinic-
行
Okay.
我想你
I thought you- -
我想你能做点教学工作  病史课
I thought you could do some teaching. Patient histories.
我的领域
My specialty.
教学相长  不觉得吗
When you teach, you learn so much. Don't you think?
这纯粹就是报复
It's all about the giving back.
老好人卡迪  总是在算计
Good old Cuddy. Always thinking.
她安排你们去询问病人病史了吗
She assign you a patient to interview?
那么你们还在这里干嘛
Then why are you still here?
为什么我们接这个病人
Why are we on this case?
因为威尔森让豪斯帮忙
'Cause Wilson asked House to do him a favor.
我觉得豪斯就是想证明她是病了
I think House just wants to prove she's sick
福曼错了
so Foreman will be wrong.
哦  你们这些家伙
Oh, you boys.
我在做本职工作罢了
Hey, I'm just doing my job.
等福曼发现了她真的有癌症  他就要糗大了
Foreman's gonna be so embarrassed when he finds out she's got cancer.
我以为你病得下不来了呢
Ah. I thought you were too sick to be down here.
我得甩开那些学生  所以伪造了个寻呼
I had to get away from those students, so I faked a page.
福曼的父母  40年幸福婚姻
Foreman's parents, happily married, 40 years.
恭喜[希伯来语  多用于婚礼祝福]
Mazel tov.
福星高照啊
Kein ayin hara.
那么为何他讨厌无家可归者呢
So why does he hate homeless people?
要是有个叔叔或者祖父母曾流落街头
I mean, if it's an uncle or a grandparent,
通常他会在大学申请陈述里提到
you'd think he'd use it in his college application essay.
家庭不幸总比平均绩点4.0有竞争力
Family struggles beats a 4.0 G.P.A. Any day.
我觉得他已经有4.0了
I think he had a 4.0.
或许他就是个势利眼
Maybe he's just a snob.
真的没必要事无巨细
You really don't need to know everything about everybody.
我没必要看《橘子郡男孩》  不过看了开心
I don't need to watch The O.C., but it makes me happy.
对  狂喜啊  另一个文件是什么
Yeah, delirious. What's the other file?
威尔森·詹姆斯  青年才俊肿瘤专家
Wilson, James. Boy Wonder Oncologist.
你认识他吗
You know him?
要知道  在一些文化传统中
You know, in some cultures,
窥探朋友生活几乎是被认为是无礼行为
it's considered almost rude for one friend to spy on another.
当然   "朋友"这个词翻成瑞典语
Of course, in Swedish, the word "Friend" Can also
就是"瘸腿蠢蛋"
be translated as "Limping twerp."
你的呼机是真的响了
Did your pager really just go off,
还是你想逃避对话
or are you ditching the conversation?
为什么不能都是真的呢  走吧
Why can't both be true? Come on.
左侧卵巢非囊性实体瘤
Solid, noncystic mass on the left ovary.
5×3厘米见方
Five-by-three centimeters.
中心性坏死
Central necrosis.
唯一的疑问就是
The only question is
她是两个月内死还是3个月
whether she dies in two months or three.
天  你是对的
God. You were right.
我们回天乏术了
There's nothing we can do for her here.
不如把她送回大街上去吧
Might as well put her back on the street.
除非这不是癌症
Unless it's not cancer.
-你开玩笑  -多逗啊
- Ah, you're joking. - Well, hard not to.
癌症最有意思了
Nothing funnier than cancer.
或许是结核瘤
What if it's a tuberculoma?
她流落街头  全年无休地呼吸那些废气
She's living out on the streets, breathing all kinds of crap 24-7.
她可能得了肺结核
The odds are, she's got T.B.
为什么就不能是良性的呢
Why can't she have a nice, benign growth to go with it?
实体瘤在她卵巢内
A solid mass on her ovary.
卵巢癌的可能性更大
Ovarian cancer's way more likely.
没错  差远了
You're right. It's not even close.
开始给她用异烟肼  利福平和链霉素
Start her on I.N.H., rifampin and streptomycin.
但这是对结核瘤的治疗
But that's the treatment for a tuberculoma.
那么晚期卵巢癌怎么治
And what is the treatment for advanced ovarian cancer?
棺材
Pine box.
-给我用的是什么药  -第二剂抗生素
- What are you giving me? - A second dose of antibiotics.
要是你得的是结核瘤  会有帮助的
If you've got a tuberculoma, it should help.
我得的不是结核瘤  是吗
I don't have a tuberculoma, do I?
可能不是
Probably not.
听着  我很抱歉曾不信任你
Hey, listen. I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
对不起  我骗了你
I'm sorry I lied to you.
我故意服用了过量胰岛素
I took too much insulin on purpose.
我实在想要个睡觉的地方
I really wanted a place to sleep.
你结过婚吗  维多利亚
Were you ever married, Victoria?
不过在漫画里
But in the comic, it- Well,
就是漫画罢了  漫画都是虚构的
it's a comic. Comics are just made up.
那么詹姆斯是谁
So who's James?
真有这个人吗  还是你虚构的
Is he real, or did you make him up?
他是真的
He's real.
要我帮忙找他吗
Can I help you find him?
光  太亮了
Oh, the- the light's bright.
越来越亮了
It's getting brighter.
放松  没事
Hey, take it easy. Everything's fine.
弗利先生要伤害我  救救我
Mr. Fury wants to hurt me! Please help me!
-医生  -等等  等等
- Doctor! - Wait, wait, wait.
-坚持住  坚持住  -请把灯关了
- Hold on, hold on. - Please turn off the light!
求你  天呐
Please! Oh, God!
好了  挺住  维多利亚
All right, hold on, Victoria.
挺住  放松  没事
Hold on. Take it easy. Everything's fine.
-烫  -都会好的  维多利亚
- It's burning! - Everything's fine, Victoria.
-发烫  -挺住
- It's burning! - Hold on.
-我浑身都要烧起来了  -喝一口  喝一口
- I'm burning! - Take a sip, take a sip.
是毒药  你给我喝的是毒药
It's poison! You gave me poison!
挺住
Hold on.
放松
Take it easy.
把那该死的灯关了
Hey, turn off that damn light!
救救我  求求你
Help me, please.!
放松  放松
Take it easy. Take it easy.
坏人找不到你  有我掩护你
The bad guys can't get you here. I've got you covered.
但弗利先生不是坏人
But Mr. Fury's not the bad guy.
我才是坏人  是我  我是坏人
I'm the bad guy. It's me. I'm the bad guy.
不是结核瘤
It's not a tuberculoma.
肯定不是
Can't be.
我不知道活检结果已经出来了
I didn't know the biopsy was back.
她高烧华氏105度
Her temperature's 105.
治疗没有用  是癌症
The treatment's not working. It's cancer.
她奄奄一息了
She's dying.
-105度  -好消息
- 105. - Good news.
-是结核瘤  -你怎么知道的
- It's a tuberculoma. - How do you figure that?
她高烧得吓人
Her temp's through the roof.
活检报告  结核瘤无误
The lab results from the biopsy. It's definitely a tuberculoma.
那么  我们的诊断是对的
So, we're right about the diagnosis,
可是相应的治疗却要害死她
and the treatment for that diagnosis is killing her.
棒极了
Perfect.
实验室复查了活检
The lab checked the biopsy again, twice.
好吧  结核瘤不会导致105度高烧
Well, a tuberculoma doesn't give you a temperature of 105.
那么就是结核瘤和其他什么
Then it's a tuberculoma and something else.
这"其他什么"要把她脑子烧化掉
The "Something else" Is gonna melt her brain.
水煮了
Poach.
这个比喻更恰当点
Better metaphor.
这么烫  应该是细菌引起的
A fever that high has to be bacterial.
或许活检过程中肠部破裂
Maybe the bowel got nicked in the biopsy.
我亲手做的活检  肠部没有破裂
I did the biopsy. No nick.
她可能是在大街上染上的
She could have picked up an infection on the streets.
她入院的时候并没有发烧
She didn't have a fever when I admitted her.
百忧解可能会诱发血清素综合征
The Prozac we gave her could have triggered serotonin syndrome,
能解释发烧
which would explain the fever.
不  杰弗逊医院也给她用百忧解了
No. Jefferson put her on Prozac
-没有问题  -她可能从未遵医嘱
- and it wasn't a problem. - She probably never took it!
他们很有可能只接诊了她一次
Most likely, they saw her one time
就给了个证明  把她赶出急诊室
and dumped her out of the E.R. with a scrip.
-就想你打算做的  -够了 你们两个
- Oh, just like you were gonna do! - Okay, you two.
拿把手术刀  像个医生一样解决问题
Grab some scalpels and settle this like doctors.
送血和尿细菌培养  做胸部X光检查
Send blood and urine cultures and get a chest X-ray.
好  停用百忧解
Fine, take her off the Prozac and
改用治疗血清素综合征的溴隐亭
put her on Bromocryptene for the serotonin syndrome.
要是我们想她活着到检查结果出来
Might wanna get her in an ice bath as well,
最好同时让她冰浴降温
assuming we want her to live long enough to see those test results.
我说了抱歉
I said I was sorry.
你高烧105度  要是不尽快降温
Your fever's 105. If we don't bring it down fast-
福曼  为什么这么对我
Foreman, why are you doing this to me?
我在救你的命
I'm saving your life.
不  我不想进去
No, don't make me go in there,
求你  我不想进去  求你
please. Don't make me do it, please!
我不想进去
I don't wanna go!
坚持下  你能行的
Come on. You can do this.
求你
Please.!
17岁的女性  手腕呈现擦伤
Seventeen-year-old female presents with abrasions
和明显外伤
and apparent trauma injury to her wrist.
-豪斯医生  -继续
- Dr. House? - Continue.
你在看漫画
You're reading a comic book.
你穿了件低领上衣想让人注意你的胸部
And you're calling attention to your bosom by wearing a low-cut top.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我以为我们在进行"大家来找茬"比赛
I thought we were having a"State the obvious" Contest.
我天性要强
I'm competitive by nature.
你觉得你该听我们陈述病史
I thought you were supposed to be listening to our patient histories.
不  我该教你们
No, I'm supposed to be teaching you.
要是我不用听就能教  我就更牛了
If I can do that without listening, more power to me.
-17岁女性  -这家伙要是拥有号称
- Seventeen-year-old female - If this guy's supposed to have
能抗拒地球引力的宇宙力量
uiversal power over all gravity,
他的头发怎么还是下垂的呢
how come his hair won't stay down?
太笨了
That's just stupid.
她在县里骑马时不慎落马
She fell off her horse while riding in the county fair.
不是  她是从沙滩别墅台阶上摔下来的
No, she didn't. She fell off the steps of her beach house.
你肯定走错房间了
You must have gone to the wrong room.
不敢相信  病人能躲过卡迪
Hard to believe that one patient could slip past Cuddy
仅凭手腕扭伤入院
and get herself admitted with a sprained wrist.
两个就更不可能了  哪个房间
Two seems almost impossible. What room?
2106室
Room 2106.
病人撒谎  不过通常一次撒一个
Patients lie, but usually only one lie at a time.
她体重多少
How much does she weigh?
-是她的手腕  不是体重  -体重  女士们
- It's her wrist, not her weight- - Poundage, ladies.
-顺别问下  她鼻子什么颜色  -她很瘦
- And by-the-by, what color's her nose? - She's thin.
-肤色  -这和她的手腕有什么关系
- Flesh tone? - What does this have to do with her wrist?
几乎无关
Almost nothing.
她不是低于90磅
She's either under ninety pounds
就是红鼻子  我该走了
or she has a red nose. I gotta go.
她有什么问题
What's wrong with her? -
那就是揭露谜底了
That would be telling.
我太善良了
Oh, I am just too nice.
病名是"C"打头的
It starts with "C."
-尿检阴性  -胸片也是
- Urine cultures are negative. - So is the chest X-ray.
下一个就该是阳性了吧
I assume there's a positive coming.
腰椎穿刺结果提示蛋白含量升高
Lumbar punctures reveal elevated proteins
白细胞数上升
and white counts.
-脑脊液培养呢  -进行中
- C.S.F. Cultures? - Still brewing.
革兰氏染色没有结果  看着像脑膜炎
Nothing on gram stain. It looks like meningitis.
我们知道绝对是感染  知道感染部位
We know it's definitely an infection, and we know where it is.
脑膜炎合理简单
Well, meningitis is nice and simple.
隔离她  用头孢曲松
Get her in isolation and start her on Ceftriaxone.
她要不好转  要不完蛋
Either she gets better, or she dies.
告诉我结果
Let me know which one happens.
老天  给她用了镇静剂的
Oh, my God! She was sedated.
一定是失效了
It must have worn off.
我半小时前亲自给的药
I did it myself a half hour ago.
我去护士站问问
I'll check the nurse's station.
柯林达伊卡
Calendraica.
她会死在外面的
She's gonna die out there.
用了10毫克氟哌丁苯制剂
You don't walk out of a room
是无法离开房间的
with 10 milligrams of Haldol in your system.
走都不能走
You don't walk at all.
我可给她注射了10毫克啊
It was 10 milligrams! I gave it to her.
不重要了  细菌性脑膜炎  高感染性
It doesn't matter! Bacterial meningitis- highly contagious.
要是她出了医院  我们绝对要负责的
If she is out of the hospital, we are so liable.
不用担心  她感染别人前就会完蛋
Not to worry. She'll be dead before she can kill anybody.
监控录像确认了  她偷了衣服  跑了
Security tape confirms it. She stole some clothes and she's gone.
衣服错了  大衣在衣柜里  干洗过了
Wrong coat. The cape's in the closet. I had it cleaned.
-有意思  -你打算救她吗
- Funny. - You gonna save her?
在她的漫画里  弗利先生住斯隆港
In her comics, Mr. Fury lives in Sloan Harbor.
入院那晚  她在斯隆街1408号发狂
The night she came in, she was at a rave at 1408 Sloan Street.
你看了漫画  天啊  斗转星移啊
You've been reading. My, how you've changed.
你是医生  做医生该做的
You are a doctor. Do what doctors do.
拿起电话  拨911
Pick up the phone, dial 911,
然后警察那头会做他们份内的事
and a cop on the other end does what cops do...
去找失踪人士
and finds the missing person.
我想剩下的有医生分内的事要做
I assume the rest of you have doctor things to do.
我知道你有
I know you do.
卡-里二氏病
Cacchi-Ricci Disease.
知道那是什么吗
Do you even know what that is?
还是你就是随便猜个C开头的
Or are you just guessing everything that starts with "C"?
肾脏问题可能导致体重下降
The kidney problems could result in weight loss.
卡-里二氏病  C-A-C-
Cacchi. C-A-C-
老天  她还真按字母顺序来的
Oh, geez, she's going alphabetically.
医生  你为什么带那个鸟的别针
Doctor, why are you wearing that bird pin?
能衬出我的眼睛
It sets off my eyes.
你好  约迪  我是豪斯医生
Hi, Jodi. I'm Dr. House.
你为什么入院的
What brings you to the hospital?
我的手腕
My wrist.
怎么回事
How did that happen?
那时我在坐摩天轮
I was riding the Ferris wheel,
然后有个巨型海鸥朝我飞来
and this huge seagull flew right at me.
太恐怖了
How horrifying.
我冲着它挥胳膊  结果撞到了摩天轮
I swung my arm at the bird, but I hit the Ferris wheel.
都是她编的吗
She's making it all up?
没有  她的手腕真伤了
No, her wrist really does hurt.
我没撒谎
I'm not lying.
当然撒了  你根本不知道发生什么
Of course you are. You have no idea what happened.
你的记忆一片空白
You have no memory.
科萨科夫综合征
Korsakoff's syndrome.
过量饮酒或营养不良导致大脑损伤
Her brain is damaged by excessive drinking or insufficient diet,
显然是后者
pretty obviously the latter.
她没有新的记忆  没有思维
She has no new memories, no new ideas.
甚至不能处理这个事实
Can't even process that idea.
所以大脑用视觉线索尽可能填补断层
So her brain fills the gaps as best it can using visual clues.
你衣服上的马让她联想到骑马事故
The horse on your shirt led her to the riding accident,
你笔记板上的冲浪带她去了海滩
and the surfscene on your clipboard led her to the beach.
"科萨科夫综合征"不是C开头的
"Korsakoff" Doesn't start with a "C."
我没说C
I didn't say "C."
我说了吗
Or did I?
学好了
Lesson to be learned-
把所有人都要当成科萨科夫综合征患者
treat everybody as if they have Korsakoff's.
我们都撒谎
We all lie anyway.
马上给她用维生素B1  她很快会没事
Give her thiamine right away. She'll bounce back pretty quickly.
然后让她吃点蛋糕冰淇淋
And then get her to eat some cake and ice cream.
什么
Yes?
你非要那么残忍吗  我觉得她在哭
Did you need to be so cruel? I think she's crying.
你好  约迪  我是豪斯医生
Hi, Jodi. I'm Dr. House.
你的手腕怎么了
What happened to your wrist?
有个古怪的老头  他有个拐杖
There was this weird old guy. He had a cane.
看见没  她若无其事
See? It's like it never happened.
忘得一干二净
Perfect forgiveness.
-心率加快  -你测体温了吗
- Pulse is rapid. - You got a temp?
不知道  她很热 不过
Don't know. She's warm, but
或许有什么可以查查  她有脑膜炎
might be something to look into. She has meningitis.
对不起  我更担心她心跳过快
Sorry. I was more worried about her heart blowing up.
脉搏150
Pulse is 150.
-心律正常吗  -是
- Rhythm regular? - Yeah.
准备  1  2  3
Ready? One, two, three.
-在哪里找到她的  -州立战场公园
- Where'd you find her? - Battlefield State Park.
-她是窄QRS波群房室折返性心动过速吗  -嗯
- She narrow complex? - Uh-huh.
-她不是在斯隆吗  -她晕倒在草地上
- She wasn't at Sloan? - She was just passed out on the grass.
福曼  我要福曼
Foreman. I need Foreman.
好  室上性心动过速
All right. Supraventricular tachycardia.
上1毫克腺苷  静推
Get me adenosine, one milligram, I.V. Push.
马上  谢谢
Right away. Thank you.
坚持住
Hang in there.
心率失常稳定住了
Her arrhythmia's stabilized.
说不通啊
Doesn't make sense.
什么能导致她的心率到150  脱水吗
what would push her heart rate over 150? Dehydration?
-高烧  -不像啊  都不可能啊
- Fever? - Unlikely. By themselves, neither one would do it.
我们一定错了  不是脑膜炎
We must be wrong about the meningitis.
可能是器质性心脏病
Maybe it's structural heart disease.
你给予腺苷后  她的心率下来了
Her heart rate dropped when you administered the adenosine.
马上就降下来了
In two seconds.
还是脑膜炎
It's still meningitis.
若是如此  延误治疗
If it is, with the delay in treatment,
那岂不是回天乏术
she's-she's got almost no chance.
开始治疗
Start the treatment.
看报告  我发现她躺在草地上
Read the report. I found her lying on the grass.
你该看我的报告  我总是瞎编
You should read my reports. I make up stuff all the time.
到底发生什么了
What really happened?
好吧  既然你
Well, since it's you-
我发现她躺在草地上
I found her lying on the grass.
好枪啊
That is a great-looking gun.
不是枪  是泰瑟枪
It's not a gun. It's a Taser.
看着很棒  干什么用的
It's so cool-looking. What does it do?
发射6万伏电压吗
Fire about 60,000 volts?
至少这能让人的心率飙到150
At least that's what it would take to jack someone's heart up to 150.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
就算我告诉你发生什么了
Let's just say I tell you what happened.
就你知我知  好吗
It stays between you and me. Right?
我发现她  躺在草地上
I found her lying on the grass.
好吧
Fine.
别告诉我
Don't tell me.
告诉我朋友  本·富兰克林
Tell my friend, Ben Franklin.
沃顿医生请到实验室
Dr. Wharton to the research lab.
我看过不少警匪片
I watch a lot of cop shows.
好消息是
The good news is,
心率和她的病情无关
the heart rate thing is not connected to her condition.
那么她快完了
Well, then she's dying,
因为脑膜炎治疗没有起效  病情在恶化
'cause the meningitis treatment isn't helping her. She's getting worse.
还有个坏消息
Well, that brings us to the bad news.
警察电击了她
The cop Tasered her.
混蛋  大概来不及掏真枪
Jerk. Probably couldn't get to his real gun fast enough.
他第一次电击在大腿
First time he hit her in the thigh...
她没有停下来  若无其事的继续走
and she just kept going, like it was nothing.
大概在这里
Right about here.
她感觉不到泰瑟枪
She didn't feel the Taser.
-局部麻痹吗  -对  就那一处
- Localized numbness? - Yeah, in that one spot.
糖尿病吗
The diabetes?
不是
I don't think so.
没有酒精  不是卡压综合征
Well, no alcohol. Not entrapment syndrome.
也不可能是维生素缺乏
Can't be a vitamin deficiency.
我们不能排查每一种感觉神经病变
We can't chase down every sensory neuropathy.
-她咬的这里吗  -对
- Is that where she bit you? - Yeah.
干嘛
What the hell!
要是你没感觉到  你就不会发怒
Can't get angry if you don't feel anything.
首先  是局部性麻痹
First, there's localized numbness,
接着是光敏感
then sensitivity to light,
方向障碍  妄想
disorientation, paranoia,
镇静剂无效  然后恐水
ineffectiveness of sedatives, and then hydrophobia.
怕水
Fear of water.
狂犬病
Rabies.
过去20年里  才10例
There have only been, what, 10 cases in the last 20 years?
对  因为有家可归的人被咬了
Yeah, that's because nonhomeless people, when they get bitten,
都会去打针
they get shots.
那里有蝙蝠
There were bats.
她没救了
She's dying.
无药可治啊
There's no treatment.
她还能活多久
How much time does she have?
一天  或许两天
A day. Maybe two.
要是你不赶紧在3小时内打针
And if you don't get your shot in the next, say, three hours,
我得再来一次反歧视聘用行动
I'm gonna have to make another affirmative action hire.
来吧
Come on.
动手吧
Do it.
要我和她说吗
You want me to talk to her?
说什么呢
And say what?
有些没有疗效的试验性疗法
"There's some experimental treatment that's not gonna work"?
还是说"不过别担心  我们会让你好受些的"
"But don't worry, we can make you comfortable"?
不重要了
Doesn't matter.
现在  她要在那间房间里死去
Now she's gonna die in that room.
对
Yeah.
这就是你能和她说的
That's what you say to her.
按住  歇会
Keep that there and rest for a minute.
告诉豪斯我要出去大概1小时
Tell House I need to go out for about an hour.
她的时间可能没那么多了
She may not have that long.
我不想她孤独的死去
I don't want her to die alone.
你要去找詹姆斯
You're going to find James.
我得试试
I'm gonna try.
我不得不说  他在这个地方下足了功夫
Well, I must say, he's done a lot with the place.
有人吗
Hello?
这里
This is it.
老天  很久没人住了
Man. No one's been in here for a long time.
一定是詹姆斯
It's gotta be James.
或许有其它地址
Maybe there's another address.
那不是詹姆斯
That's notJames.
是保罗
Paul.
保罗·菲利亚
Paul Furia.
弗利先生
Mr. Fury.
她丈夫
Her husband.
那么詹姆斯是谁
Then who's James?
她孩子
Her kid.
我真想咬咬你  太可爱了
Aw, I just wanna eat you up. You're so delicious.!
看着我
Aw, look at me.
和你爸爸一模一样
You're just like your papa.
看看你  就像你爸爸
Look at you! Just like your dad.
福曼
Foreman.
Foreman?
他们死了
They're dead.
两年前的车祸
That car crash two years ago-
她断了胳膊  他们死了
She broke her arm, and they were killed.
她开的车
She was driving.
詹姆斯
James.
不
No.
-是保罗  -保罗吗
- It's Paul. - Paul?
你来带我走吧
You've come to take me.
不是
No.
我是来原谅你的
I've come to forgive you.
不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
很抱歉  很抱歉
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
我知道
I know.
没事的  维多利亚
It's okay, Victoria.
没事了
It's okay.
你跟踪我吗
You followed me?
没有
No.
今天你穿了雨靴
You were wearing rain boots today,
但你把车停在地下停车场了
but you were parked in the underground garage,
所以你穿雨靴唯一的理由就是你想走路
so the only reason you'd need boots was if you were hitting the streets.
我跟踪了你
I followed you.
-我不是说过不该窥探朋友的隐私吗  -对
- Didn't we have a conversation about friendship? - Yeah.
我有些后续的疑问
I had some follow-up questions.
我见过你的父母  兄弟
I've met your parents and your brother.
我有2个兄弟
I have two brothers.
-为什么不告诉我  -无关紧要
- Why wouldn't you tell me - It wasn't relevant.
为什么
Why not?
因为他不再是我生活的一部分了
Because he's not in my life anymore.
这样的话  就是有关的
Well, that's relevant.
这是我最后见到他的地方
This was the last place I saw him.
9年前
Nine years ago.
我都不知道他是否还在人世
I don't even know if he's alive.